The answer is no, we're not done yet.
答案是不行 还没结束
We have reached a goal state.
我们到达了目标状态
We put a path onto the frontier that reaches the goal Bucharest,
把通往目的地布加勒斯特的路径放到边缘上
but we haven't popped that path off the frontier.
但我们还没有将路径从边缘上弹出
And uniform costs search continues to search until we pop it off the frontier.
在我们将其从边缘上弹出之前 一致代价搜索会继续进行
We continue looking to see if there's a better path that also reaches the goal.
继续查找是否有更好的路径可抵达目标
So, let's see I forgot to say Fagaras is explored,
我们来看看 我忘了说 弗格拉什已经探索好了
so let's continue looking on the frontier,
我们继续看边缘
the cheapest now is here at 299.
现在代价最小的是这条 299 的
We'll expand that.
扩展出来
We get a path of cost 374.
得到路径代价值为 374
Put that on the frontier.
将其放到边缘上
Now let's go again.
继续重复操作
Now the cheapest path is over here at 317,
现在代价最小的路径在这边 代价值为 317
we'll mark that as explored,
将其标记为已探索
and add two more pass, one here,
再添加两条路径 一条在这里
that's a worse path,
这条代价值较大
so it gets dropped,
所以排除掉
and one path that also reaches the goal,
另一条也能抵达目标
and that has a total cost of 418.
总代价为 418
So that just shows it's a good thing we waited,
这就说明等待是有回报的
a good thing we didn't stop when we found the first path to the goal
没有一找到第一条通往目标的路径就停下来是件好事
because now this second path found is actually cheaper than the first path found.
因为现在找到的这第二条路径比第一条代价小
But we're not going to stop here because we still haven't popped
但我们还不到停止的时候 因为还没有把
off a path that reaches the goal. So we'll continue.
通往目标的路径弹出 所以我们继续
What's next, now the cheapest path on the frontier is here at 366.
接下来 边缘上代价最小的路径为这条 366 的
We expand that and we get past that or worse paths to points we've already seen before.
扩展该路径 来到一条代价较大的路径上 而且这条路径通向的节点我们之前见过了
So nothing new goes on the frontier.
所以边缘不会添加任何新路径
Next, the cheapest path on the frontier is at 374,
接下来 边缘上代价最小的路径为 374 的这条
again expanding that leads nothing useful,
将其扩展开来 还是没什么好结果
only worse paths than we've seen before.
得到的路径比我们之前看到的更差
And now, finally, the cheapest path on the frontier is this 418 path to Bucharest.
最后 边缘上前往布加勒斯特而代价又最小的路径为这条 418 的
So we pop that off and now we reach the goal and now we stop.
所以将其弹出 抵达目标 现在我们可以停止了
So even though we found the 460 path first,
所以虽然我们先找到了 460 的路径
we don't stop there because there might be
但我们没有停在那里 因为可能还有其它路径
another path that also reaches the goal that's cheaper.
能抵达目标 而且代价更小
We keep on going until we pop path off of the frontier that reaches the goal,
所以算法继续进行 直到我们将通往目标的路径从边缘上弹出
and that's why uniform cost search is guaranteed to find the cheapest path to the goal.
这就是为什么一致代价搜索保证能找出通往目标且代价最小的路径